Guide to the Records of the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute AD.RG.024.1
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
NYU Abu Dhabi Institute: Promotional and Program Materials
2007-2020
2008-2015
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
AD.RG.024.1
7 Linear Feet in 2 legal size document boxes; 1 OS Flat File; 3 [16x20] OS boxes of 343 DVDs; 159 USB flash drives
159 Items [individual USB drives]
197 Megabytes stored in the CDS-ASC repository
The collection "Records of the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute: Public Program Materials" documents over ten years' worth of events that took place at the Institute from 2007 through 2020, with the majority of the contents covering the years 2008 through 2015. This body of material from the Institute's first decade is relevant to anyone researching the early years of NYU Abu Dhabi as a way to understand the University's regional and global role in advancing research and scholarship, and exchanging knowledge collaboratively with the wider public.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The initial three increments of this collection were transferred to the University Archives in March 2019, with further accretions expected.
Arrangement
RG 24-1 is arranged into four series. 1. Calendars, Promotional Materials, and Program Brochures, 2008-2018. 2. Photographic Materials: Prints and Contact Sheets [ca. 2008-2013]. 3. NYUAD Institute Yearbooks, 2008-2019. 4. Audiovisual event and program files, 2007-2015. Materials are arranged chronologically in each series by date of event.
Biographical / Historical
New York University, in developing a new "Global Network" of degree granting campuses and academic centers across six continents (NYU New York, NYU Abu Dhabi, and NYU Shanghai), established the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute in 2008, two years prior to the Abu Dhabi campus opening its doors to its first class of students and faculty. The Institute was the first "on-the-ground" operation of the University in the UAE. As a research outreach and sponsorship component, it was established to create and support innovative research programs, organize public discussions with experts from around the world, and invite participation not only from and for the NYU network constituency but also from and for local, regional, and national communities.
The Institute's inaugural program in October 2008, "On the Art of the Novel," featured renowned Lebanese novelist Elias Khoury. Its "first collaboration" came during the November 2008 program "Stephen Hawking's 'A Briefer History of Time'," featuring the Arabic translation of that book by Kalima, the translation initiative launched by Abu Dhabi Authority for Culture and Heritage (ADACH). In December of 2008, "Neurolinguistics and Imaging: Progress and Prospects" was the first multi-day program that the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute sponsored. Early events took place at the Al Mamoura Auditorium in Abu Dhabi.
NYU Abu Dhabi Institute programming was early-on a joint effort between faculty and administration in Abu Dhabi, and faculty and administrative leadership in New York. The Institute created an Advisory Committee that also first convened in Decmeber 2008, and in May of 2009, the NYUAD offices at 19 Washington Square North sponsored the first New York-hosted Institute event, a lecture titled "Building Big: A Critical Examination of the Planning of Mega Urban Transportation." The Institute continues to organize programs in both Abu Dhabi and New York. When the NYU Abu Dhabi downtown campus was built and finally available as a venue for programs, the Institute hosted its first on-campus lecture there in December 2009, "The Predictioneer's Game," a talk about game theory with NYU Professor Bruce Bueno de Mesquita. Student-centered Institute programming was introduced in 2011 with the "Hackathon for Social Good in the Arab World."
Today, the NYUAD Institute continues to sponsor and support multi-day conferences, workshops and seminars relevant to the NYUAD curriculum and areas of research, across a range of subjects from falconry to poetry to genomics to youth unemployment crises. The Institute has become an important asset of the university that seeks to deepen understanding of the world, generate important new knowledge, and facilitate breakthrough discoveries in science and technology.
References and for further information: "10 Years: Celebrating the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute"
Related Materials
Users and researchers may find additional resources on the NYU Abu Dhabi Institue YouTube Channel.
Scope and Contents
The collection "Records of the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute: Public Program Materials" documents over ten years' worth of events that took place at the Institute from 2007 through 2020, with the majority of the contents covering the years 2008 through 2015. This body of material from the Institute's first decade will be of interest to anyone researching the early years of NYU Abu Dhabi as a way to understand the University's regional and global role in advancing research and scholarship, and exchanging knowledge collaboratively with the wider public.
Materials include printed calendars; promotional cards, flyers, and brochures; a small collection of printed photographic materials; published "Year in Review" yearbooks; and audiovisual files (photos, videos, slide presentations) from over 300 events sponsored by the Institute from 2007-2015.
The series "Calendars, Promotional Materials, and Program Brochures" is a collection of printed materials that were displayed, distributed and mailed as invitations, covering the years 2008-2014.
The small series "Photographic Materials" separates out some of the printed photographs and contact sheets from early events (although, users should note that the majority of event photos have been preserved as part of the audiovisual series).
A full set of published yearbooks, the Institute's annually published "Year in Review," offers highlights and overviews of each year's programming.
Finally, this collection's audiovisual series offers not only a detailed inventory of what the collection contains as far as photographed and video-recorded events, but also information about associated program officers and speakers, as well as external links to online published clips and videos for selected events, hosted on the Institute's YouTube channel.
Research institutes; Universities and Colleges -- institutes; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; NYU Abu Dhabi
- Calendars, Promotional Materials and Program Brochures, 2008-2014
  Scope and Contents
  A collection of printed materials that were displayed, distributed and mailed as invitations, covering the years 2008-2014.
  - Institute Event Calendar/Brochure Prep Notes, Fall 2008 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Preliminary Program Schedule, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Institute Event Calendars, 2008-2013 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Washington Square Institute Event Calendars, 2012-2013 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Institute Event Invitation Announcement Cards, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Institute Event Posters (oversize), Fall 2009 (Map-case 1.C)
  - Institute Event Announcements/Posters, Spring 2010 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Institute Event Program Brochures [incomplete set], 2009-2014 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Program: Embracing Sports in the UAE, November 19-20, 2014 (Box 1)
  - Press Kit, February 2008-February 2010 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Photographic Materials: Photo prints and Contact Sheets, [ca. 2008 - 2013]
  This is a small series that separates out some of the printed photographs and contact sheets from early events that were transferred with records to the University Archives (users should note that the majority of event photos are digital, and have been preserved as part of the Audiovisual Event Files series).
  - Photographs, January 2009 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Photo Contact Sheets: Brain Imaging, January 14, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Photo Contact Sheets: Search for Social Entrepreneurship, January 18, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Photo Contact Sheets: Education, Media, and Human Development, January 20, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- NYUAD Institute Yearbooks, 2010 -
  The NYUAD Institute publishes an annual "Year in Review," a yearbook highlighting major events throughout the year. This series includes selected print copies of the publication, as well as E-book versions.
  Note: copies of the NYUAD Institute Year in Review are also in the NYUAD Publications and Ephemera Collection (AD-RG-2), as well as the Records of the Office of Public Affairs: Publications (AD-RG-9).
  - Year In Review, 2010-2011 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Yearbook, 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Year In Review, 2011-2012 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Yearbook, 2011-2012 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Year In Review, 2012-2013 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Year In Review, 2013-2014 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Year In Review, 2014-2015 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Year In Review, 2015-2016 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Year in Review, 2015-2016 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Year in Review, 2016-2017 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Year in Review, 2016-2017 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Year In Review, 2017-2018 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Year in Review, 2017-2018 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Year In Review, 2018-2019 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Year in Review, 2018-2019 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Year In Review, 2019-2020 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Year in Review, 2020-2021 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Year in Review, 2022-2023 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Anniversary Commemorative Yearbooks/Publications, 2013; 2018
  - Five Years: Celebrating the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute, 2013 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 10 Years: Celebrating 10 Years of the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute, 2018 (Box 3, Folder 2)